Stewart Newburgh Airport Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Stewart Newburgh Airport Collection
1992 - 1998
NPkMC-222-216
4.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Stewart Newburgh Airport
Although Stewart International Airport was originally an air force base, it was deactivated in 1970 and began running commercial airlines in 1989. This called for changes and an administration to oversee the running of the airport; thus the Stewart Master Plan and Stewart Airport Commission were born. This collection contains various papers, reports, correspondence, and clippings from these two areas.
Collection Overview
The Stewart Newburgh Airport Collection contains various papers, correspondence, reports, and clippings from the ‘90s regarding changes and the upkeep of the airport. Included are documents concerning airport terminal expansion and privatization of the airport.
Acquisitions Information
The collection was donated to Marist College in memory of Geraldine Geller.
Historical Note
In 1930, Archie Stewart gave 220 acres of land to Newburgh in order to begin an airport. By 1948, the airport had changed to Stewart Air Force Base. Even though it was deactivated in 1970 as an air force base, hostages in Iran returned home to this air space in January of 1981. Later, it was handed over to the State of New York and started scheduling passenger flights in 1989. The year of 1993 began the first meeting of the Airport Master Plan Update Working Group, and then in 2000 Stewart International Airport became officially privatized. Today, the airport services people everyday, with a new expanded terminal.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into two subseries: 1) Stewart Master Plan, with five subseries, and 2) Stewart Airport Commission, with six subseries.
- 1. Stewart Master Plan, 1; Boxes: 1 - 5
  Series contains reports and regional planning
  Chronological
  - Subseries 1.1: General Reports, 1.1; Box: 1
    - Airport Master Plan Update - Draft Technical Report. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, February 1995 (attached correspondence). (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Airport Master Plan Update - Draft Technical Report, Chapter Eight: Implementation Program. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, March 1995. (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Environmental Reports, 1.2; Boxes: 2 - 3
    - correspondence, reports, and meeting agendas and summaries (1992) (Folder 1, Box 2)
    - Final Federal Environmental Impact Statement - Vol. I. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, United States Department of Transportation, and Federal Aviation Administration, July 1992 (attached correspondence). (Folder 3, Box 2)
    - Final Federal Environmental Impact Statement - Vol. II. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, United States Department of Transportation, and Federal Aviation Administration, July 1992. (Folder 4, Box 2)
    - Final Federal Environmental Impact Statement - Vol. III. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, United States Department of Transportation, and Federal Aviation Administration, July 1992 (attached notice). (Folder 5, Box 2)
    - Final Federal Environmental Impact Statement - Vol. IV. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, United States Department of Transportation, and Federal Aviation Administration, July 1992. (Folder 6, Box 3)
    - FAR Part 150 Noise Study - Draft Technical Report; Part One: Noise Exposure Maps, Part Two: Airport Noise Compatibility Plan. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, February 1995. (Folder 7, Box 3)
    - FAR Part 150 Noise Study Technical Report. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, July 1996. (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.3: Airport Planning, 1.3; Box: 4
    - terminal expansion (1994) (Folder 2, Box 4)
    - Working Group (1992- 1993) (Folder 3, Box 4)
    - Advisory Circular - Airport Master Plans. Washington, D.C.: US Department of Transportation - Federal Aviation Administration, June 1985. (Folder 9, Box 4)
    - Airport Master Plan - Draft Chapter Four: Forecasts of Aviation Demand. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, September 1993 (attached correspondences). (Folder 10, Box 4)
    - Airport Master Plan - Draft Chapter Five: Facility Analysis. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, March 1994 (attached correspondence). (Folder 11, Box 4)
    - The Tri- State Competitive Region Initiative. Regional Plan Association, March 24, 1994 (date from attached correspondence). (Folder 12, Box 4)
    - Airport Master Plan - Draft Chapter Six: Alternatives Analysis. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, July 1994 (attached correspondence and working group packet). (Folder 13, Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.4: Airport Proposals, 1992 - 1995; 1.4; Box: 4
    - management and hotel proposals (1992- 1995) (Folder 4, Box 5)
    - Proposals for the Provision of Business Development, Public Affairs and Lease Negotiation Services at Stewart International Airport. New Jersey: airport Corporation of America, April 25, 1994. (Folder 14, Box 5)
    - A Proposal for the Operation, Management and Continued Development of Stewart International Airport - Vol. I. New York: Stewart Work Force - Technical/Management, April 25, 1994. (Folder 15, Box 5)
    - A Proposal for the Operation, Management and Continued Development of Stewart International Airport - Vol. II. New York: Stewart Work Force - Technical/Management, April 25, 1994. (Folder 16, Box 5)
    - Proposal to Provide Management Services to Stewart International Airport. California: Lockheed Air Terminal, Inc., April 25, 1994 (separate). (Folder 17, Box 5)
  - Subseries 1.5: Miscellaneous, 1.5; Box: 5
    - various papers, notes, and articles (1992) (Folder 5, Box 5)
- 2. Stewart Airport Commission, 1994 - 1998; 2; Boxes: 6 - 13
  Series contains meeting minutes and documents
  - Subseries 2.1: Meetings, 1996 - 1998; 2.1; Boxes: 6 - 11
    Series contains seeting minutes and documents
    - January 30, 1996 (Folder 6, Box 6)
    - February 27, 1996 (Folder 7, Box 6)
    - March 26, 1996 (Folder 8, Box 6)
    - April 26, 1996 (Folder 9, Box 6)
    - May 28, 1996 (Folder 10, Box 6)
    - June 25, 1996 (Folder 11, Box 6)
    - July 30, 1996 (Folder 12, Box 6)
    - August 27, 1996 (Folder 13, Box 7)
    - September 24, 1996 (Folder 14, Box 7)
    - October 29, 1996 (Folder 15, Box 7)
    - November 26, 1996 (Folder 16, Box 8)
    - December 17, 1996 (Folder 17, Box 8)
    - January 28, 1997 (Folder 18, Box 8)
    - February 25, 1997 (Folder 19, Box 8)
    - March 25, 1997 (Folder 20, Box 8)
    - April 29, 1997 (Folder 21, Box 8)
    - May 27, 1997 (Folder 22, Box 8)
    - June 24, 1997 (Folder 23, Box 9)
    - July 29, 1997 (Folder 24, Box 9)
    - August 26, 1997 (Folder 25, Box 9)
    - September 30, 1997 (Folder 26, Box 9)
    - October 28, 1997 (Folder 27, Box 10)
    - November 25, 1997 (Folder 28, Box 10)
    - December 30, 1997 (Folder 29, Box 10)
    - January 27, 1998 (Folder 30, Box 10)
    - February 24, 1998 (Folder 31, Box 10)
    - March 31, 1998 (Folder 32, Box 11)
    - April 28, 1998 (Folder 33, Box 11)
    - May 26, 1998 (Folder 34, Box 11)
    - June 30, 1998 (Folder 35, Box 11)
    - July 28, 1998 (Folder 36, Box 11)
    - August 25, 1998 (Folder 37, Box 11)
    - September 29, 1998 (Folder 38, Box 11)
    - October 1998 (Folder 39, Box 11)
  - Subseries 2.2: Business Development, 1995 - 1997; 2.2; Box: 12
    - documents from 1995- 1996 (Folder 40, Box 12)
    - NYS Department of Transportation Agreement with Lockheed Air Terminal of New York, Inc. for Operational Services, Business Development Public Affairs and Lease Negotiations at Stewart International Airport. New York: New York State Department of Transportation, 1995. (Folder 18, Box 12)
    - Airport Strategic Plan for Business Development Public Affairs and Lease Negotiations. New York: Airport Group, New York, Inc., 1996- 1997. (Folder 19, Box 12)
  - Subseries 2.3: Privatization, 1994 - 1996; 2.3; Box: 12
    - correspondence and attached documents (1995- 1996) (Folder 41, Box 12)
    - clippings (1994- 1996) (Folder 42, Box 12)
    - various notes, reports, and flyers (Folder 43, Box 12)
    - Airport Privatization: Issues Related to the Sale or Lease of U.S. Commercial Airports. Washington, D.C.: United States General Accounting Office, November 1996. (Folder 20, Box 12)
  - Subseries 2.4: State Comptroller’s Audit of Selected Capital Projects, 1995; 2.4; Box: 12
    - comments on audit recommendations with attached correspondence (1995) (Folder 44, Box 12)
    - Department of Transportation: Capital Program at Stewart Airport, Report 94- S- 51. New York: State of New York Office of the State Comptroller Division of Management Audit, May 30, 1995 (attached correspondence). (Folder 21, Box 12)
  - Subseries 2.5: Stewart Raceway, 1994 - 1995; 2.5; Box: 12
    - general correspondence with attached documents (1995) (Folder Folder 45, Box 12)
    - Empire Motorsports Proposal correspondence (1994- 1995) (Folder 46, Box 12)
    - clippings (1994- 1995) (Folder 47, Box 12)
    - various notes, reports, and flyers (Folder 48, Box 12)
  - Subseries 2.6: Miscellaneous, 1991 - 1998; 2.6; Box: 13
    - Friends of the Hudson Valley Report, August 1995 (Folder 49, Box 13)
    - clippings with attached correspondence (1995) (Folder 50, Box 13)
    - correspondence with attachments (1991- 1998) (Folder 51, Box 13)
    - various notes and papers (Folder 52, Box 13)